<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[KotSF]]></title><description><![CDATA[The KotSF blog]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 02:49:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[How Necessary Are Those Expenses?]]></title><description><![CDATA[One of the key elements of personal finance is separating "needs" from
"wants". Every guide to controlling your budget usually starts with…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/how-necesse-expenses/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/how-necesse-expenses/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;One of the key elements of personal finance is separating &quot;needs&quot; from
&quot;wants&quot;. Every guide to controlling your budget usually starts with
this. However, there&apos;s not a lot of guidance in deciding between one and the
other. A lot of the reason there&apos;s not is probably that this is a very personal
process. What one person considers a frivolity, another person might consider a
necessity. It&apos;s up to each of us to decide what things we value and then shift
our budgets accordingly to prioritize spending where it counts and avoid things
we can do without.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the new year, I&apos;m going to try implementing a new system. In reviewing my
expenses from the last year, I&apos;ve decided to assign them each a priority level
of 1-5 based on the criteria below. I don&apos;t expect everyone would have the same
values as I do in regards of how to prioritize spending, but I think simply
labelling things neccessary or unnecessary is too coarse to be useful. Instead,
I&apos;m going to try to be more mindful of what purpose I&apos;m trying to achieve with
each purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Survive - Necessary for survival: This includes things like rent, utilities,
groceries that I need to stay alive. I&apos;m also including Internet access and
mobile phone service. While I technically could live without them, it&apos;s pretty
tough to have any sort of normal, modern life without these.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prosper - Not strictly necessary, but beneficial: Honestly, this is probably
the most ill-defined category. Here I&apos;m including things that I don&apos;t really
&lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt;, but which provide a practical benefit that I deem greater than the
cost. Things like furniture, new clothes, my car and all its related expenses,
and soon a cleaning service. These expenses make life easier and provide me more
time to do things I like, but if I absolutely had to, I could get rid of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect - Fun with friends: These expenses are, in a sense, unnecessary, but they
involve building relationships with friends and family and for that reason I
value them higher than things which only entertain myself. This includes things
like eating at restaurants, having drinks with friends, gifts, and travel to
visit friends and family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy - Fun alone: These are things that I enjoy, but don&apos;t really need. This
includes entertainment that I only use by myself or conveniences that I could
have avoided with better planning. Examples are tv services (netflix, etc.),
books to read for pleasure, eating out for lunch or getting coffee at work,
take-out food. I really don&apos;t need to buy these things, but at least I got some
enjoyment out of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid - Waste, Mistakes: These are things I didn&apos;t want to spend money on and
that could have been avoided. This includes things like speeding tickets,
parking tickets, repairs to things damaged by negligence or carelessness,
etc. This category &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be zero. That will be the goal for 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how did I do last year? I went through and ranked every purchase I made by
adding a number one through five as a note in Mint. I then exported the data
from mint and used a little &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandas.pydata.org/&quot;&gt;pandas&lt;/a&gt; magic to tally
up the totals for each priority and draw a little pie chart with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://matplotlib.org/&quot;&gt;matplotlib&lt;/a&gt;. This would be pretty easy to do in Excel
too, but I like using any chance to practice data munging with python. Anyway,
the results came out like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot; style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;  max-width: 576px;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/static/0f535f90855c2be68316b8816255464b/9b31d/priorities.png&quot; style=&quot;display: block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom: 100%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&amp;apos;data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABQAAAAUCAYAAACNiR0NAAAACXBIWXMAAAsSAAALEgHS3X78AAACYklEQVQ4y7WU30sUURTHh577B+olqESp3qIfL0EPQU9BUK9J9AdU0lNBiAki1kuraSZq1INYkVIEhS8Zme467uy2bquSixq6mz+Wdd2d2ZnZO5/GHd122HVLqDszzJ3Lmc/9nnPPORL/eEh/MrAsq/Aunu8KmP/ZvvJ3HiTY+sASoiJYqqRIWLnCurCXzd9GO0KlnWB5RfbImQLN3GBxdoqY4ieZSKDqepEnbqhUHubwvv54TZ9yicHwdZS3r5ipu8lSSwtqPOaYCGfjYpFSSeC3YjcUacAzehiP9wAvvtUSejNAvO4G8Z5ungdWiK5pTiiE233JfRAiPw/OD/Bw9CDd/lN0jB+hP3KNQG8v6w+aGZhc5rZs0RnYIJfLlYTLpdAwdLSMSb98lTZfDV0TJ2kfr6EvVIvc1cWnkSANAUHzRJb6LykisRS6msEwc26F20BNy7K8ukjn8Hk8I0dt4AnabODg5BUiMwnujWVoUgyaZZU7H1cYmUtiamkbaJZz2XFXVTWeeS/y2H/MAXqreD91l2TUwwffEI1jlg3VaZR1grFMIaVKXC7Ou3dKPa2+Q3YMT9MuVzMceYIRroKpvQSCL2kZNWnybZDMZEsyxJWHYkvlz7UF2ofP0DFRbT/HCX9/ih7aBxHbfHoPs4Fb+OdWS0qybB5uq5yPhen5fIEO7zkWZlshLJGWJXRFIhu9XHK65SsFN1RV00Tj0yzNPGJd2U8idJb5yfuk0oYr7mUVuhK7CLo5TNNOJzWFYS/p5ua3UaiQigrLtalisFPfomILk/6+F4rCZrtqX/+9Y+92/ALz593q9kBkAwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==&amp;apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot; alt=&quot;priorities&quot; title=&quot;priorities&quot; src=&quot;/static/0f535f90855c2be68316b8816255464b/9b31d/priorities.png&quot; srcset=&quot;/static/0f535f90855c2be68316b8816255464b/19bd1/priorities.png 163w,
/static/0f535f90855c2be68316b8816255464b/d3bcb/priorities.png 325w,
/static/0f535f90855c2be68316b8816255464b/9b31d/priorities.png 576w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 576px) 100vw, 576px&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think not too bad. Things are probably a &lt;em&gt;little&lt;/em&gt; higher and the
&quot;Connect&quot; side of things, but that can be remedied by relying less on having to
go out to eat or get drinks as an excuse to hang out with friends (or maybe
ordering cheaper drinks when I do). I really thought &quot;Enjoy&quot; would be a bigger
problem than it was. It seems like I give in a lot to the urge to just go out
for lunch at work, or pay $2-$3 for that afternoon cup of coffee rather than
grabbing one from the office machine. Still, this number could probably be cut
at least in half. Maybe I&apos;ll immediately transfer money to savings instead of
buying that cup of afternoon coffee as an incentive to save the money rather
than spend it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this isn&apos;t intended to be the end-all/be-all method of prioritizing
spending. Within each priority there are opportunities to save money. You need
somewhere to live to survive, but that can be a studio apartment or a mansion,
with accordingly different impacts on the budget. There are also multiple ways
to achieve each goal without spending any money. This was a helpful exercise for
me to think about what I value, and to make sure I&apos;m spending money in line with
those values.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Four Character Group Archetype]]></title><description><![CDATA[I've noticed that when a work of fiction focuses on a group of four characters,
the roles those characters play within the group fall into a…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/the-four-c-archetype/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/the-four-c-archetype/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve noticed that when a work of fiction focuses on a group of four characters,
the roles those characters play within the group fall into a pattern. It seems
to be more or less the same regardless of the gender of the group, although
these are almost always same-sex groups. The roles are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader / The Cool One: Fairly self explanatory. This character sets the
agenda and mediates disputes between other characters. The other characters
look up to them, though they may not always admit it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain / The Uptight One: Usually smart, often entrusted to come up with
the plan to achieve the goal set by the leader. Sometimes they&apos;re just fussy,
though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead / The Troubled One: This one, for me, is the most ill-defined and
varies the most. Often they have some personal demons they&apos;re fighting. If
there&apos;s a cause or a quest involved they are the most emotionally invested. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball / The Free Spirit: Light-hearted and funny, this character
provides comic relief. Sometimes they are low-status and serve as the butt of
other character&apos;s jokes, but not always.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be something about these particular archetypes that form a stable
and satisfying group dynamic. A functioning group can&apos;t have four leaders or
four goofballs, nothing would get done. These characters balance each other out
and support each other. When one&apos;s overarching modus operandi is harmful to the
situation, the others unite to compensate. When the leader pushes the group too
hard, the goofball lightens the mood. The Brain comes up with the plans, but
needs the others to execute. The Hothead is passionate and fires the group up,
inspiring them to drive forward towards their goal (Though sometimes the Hothead
can go too far. If they perceive the group isn&apos;t caring enough and they&apos;ll try
to go off on their own, requiring rescue from the rest of the group).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m focusing here on stories where the group is united in a quest towards some
common goal, which seems to often be the case. If the story is a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1Njhu3L&quot;&gt;Hero&apos;s Journey&lt;/a&gt;, the leader is often the hero, with the
rest of the group as support.  The same character types are also evident in more
open ended formats where there isn&apos;t necessarily a quest - examples below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first place I noticed this was in the movie &lt;em&gt;Stand By Me&lt;/em&gt;, as it seems
particularly pronounced there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Chris&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Gordie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - Teddy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Vern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stand By Me&lt;/em&gt; is interesting because it&apos;s &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; (so to speak) The Brain, in
that he&apos;s the narrator. Usually if there&apos;s a main character, it&apos;s The Leader,
but much of the time all four characters share the focus equally. Some other
four character ensembles where this dynamic plays out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also very obvious, and probably a better canonical example than &lt;em&gt;Stand By Me&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Leonardo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Donatello&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - Raphael&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Michelangelo &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; I&apos;ve heard tell that some people consider Raphael the leader. Unfortunately,
those people are wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Peter Venkman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Egon Spengler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - Winston Zeddmore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Ray Stantz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This is a less than perfect example. Winston is The Hothead mostly by the
process of elmination. If Ghostbusters has a failing, it&apos;s how underdeveloped
the character of Winston is, compared to the other three. It will be
interesting to see how the new Ghostbusters handles the Winston-equivalent
character. Speaking of groups of women, they hold to more or less the same
dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sex and the City&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Carrie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Charlotte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - Miranda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Samantha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I haven&apos;t seen a whole lot of this show and I&apos;m not sure I have
this right. One could make an argument for switching Charlotte and
Miranda. Samantha is much more on the &quot;Free Spirit&quot; side of Goofball / Free
Spirit type. The Goofball&apos;s role is to push the group to lighten up and take
things less seriously and sometimes provide comic relief. A lot of the time this
is accomplished by The Goofball character being naive and innocent, almost
childlike. Samantha is an interesting departure in that she accomplishes this
purpose while being decidedly &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; innocent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Girls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Hannah&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Marnie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - Jessa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Shoshanna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one puzzled me for a bit. I wanted Jessa to be the free spirit, since that
is the way she seems to view herself. By season 2 though, it becomes obvious
that Jessa isn&apos;t as carefree as she appears, and that is mostly an act to cover
up her personal struggles. Shoshanna, on the other hand, is charmingly naive
sometimes, dispensing wisdom in a from-the-mouths-of-babes type way. She plays
The Fool, who, because of her innocence, can get away with acknowledging truths
the other characters know, but delude themselves into ignoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Seinfeld&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Jerry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Elaine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - George&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Kramer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seinfeld fits so well I have to think it&apos;s deliberate. George flies off the
handle on the regular. A whole episode is devoted to Elaine retaking an IQ test
to prove how smart she is. Kramer is, well, Kramer. It&apos;s also a somewhat rare
example of a mixed-gender group. Way to be progressive, Seinfeld!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems to be a remarkably robust dynamic. It holds true even in larger
groups, where more than one character may combine to fill the same role. Take
&lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt;, for example - many more than four characters, yet they fit
the same archetypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Frodo, Sam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Gandalf, Legolas, Aragorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hothead - Gimli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Merry and Pippin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a variation, The Hothead is sometimes optional. If the characters are
sufficiently motivated by their situation and/or if the story is too
light-hearted to support someone who&apos;s dark and brooding, it&apos;s not necessary to
embody that aspect in a character. &lt;em&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/em&gt; is the most obvious example of
a three person dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Leader - Harry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Brain - Hermione&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Goofball - Ron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think the story would have been improved by the addition of a fourth
Hothead character to the main group. The direness of the impending doom of
Voldemort taking over the world is sufficient to inspire the characters to move
forward. Harry also does some double-duty by having brooding, troubled episodes
at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly, I could go on indefinitely analyzing how various different character
groups fit into this mold, as it&apos;s a lot of fun to me. I doubt it&apos;s perfect and
probably someone will be able to point out an example where it doesn&apos;t
hold. Still, I think it provides a good framework for how characters can
interact with each other in a way that is satisfying to watch. Definitely
something to keep in mind and play with if I ever write something about a group
of characters.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The One Question Every Prospective College Student Should Be Asking]]></title><description><![CDATA[Apologies for the clickbaity headline. That sort of thing isn't usually my
style. I'll cut right to the chase. The question is "What…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/the-one-qu-be-asking/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/the-one-qu-be-asking/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the clickbaity headline. That sort of thing isn&apos;t usually my
style. I&apos;ll cut right to the chase. The question is &quot;What percentage of classes
are taught by full-time faculty?&quot;. If you&apos;re already on board with why this is
important and would like to get right to the juicy, juicy data,
&lt;a href=&quot;/adjunct/colleges.html&quot;&gt;have at it&lt;/a&gt;. I&apos;ve culled the information provided by US
News and World report so that it can be re-sorted by any of the available
metrics they have (including percentage of full time faculty). In the meantime,
for some insight as to why this is important, read on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unbeknownst to the general public, academia is undergoing an identity
crisis. As tuition costs have skyrocketed, universities are being run more and
more like corporations. Two trends in particular will be very familiar to those
in the corporate world - exorbitant management salaries, and labor cost-cutting
via replacing full-time, benefit-receiving employees with part-time, contract
employees. In academia this translates to hiring fewer and fewer tenured
professors and increasingly relying on adjuncts to teach classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is an adjunct?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjunct professors are usually hired on a class-by-class basis to
teach a specific course. They are paid per course, and are only paid
for the time spent in the classroom, typically $2,500 - $4,000 per
course. Traditionally, this was a way to allow people who held
full-time jobs to share their real world experience in a university
setting and earn a little extra income. Lately, these positions are
used by recent and soon-to-be PhD graduates to cobble together a
living while they chase a shrinking pool of tenure-track teaching
positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What does this mean for students?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students should be the most concerned about the quality of instruction
they&apos;re receiving. While most adjuncts are extremely dedicated
individuals (indeed, they have to be to persevere in their fields
without secure employment), they do not possess the resources that
come with a full professorship. As
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2015/05/the-cost-of-an-adjunct/394091/?single_page=true&quot;&gt;adjunct professors themselves warn&lt;/a&gt;,
they are not provided with office space, making it difficult or
impossible to meet with students outside of class. Not being
full-time, permanent employees, adjunct professors have a limited
knowledge of the university&apos;s curriculum and policies, rendering them
unable to give advice to students about which courses to take to best
meet their educational goals. For students who plan on continuing on
to a graduate degree, they may have difficulty getting letters of
recommendation when most of their classes have been taught by
adjuncts. Since adjuncts are only hired on a per-semester basis, there
is no guarantee that the professor they had last semester will be back
next semester. If they are able to get a letter of recommendation,
students will find that a letter from an adjunct professor carries
less influence with admissions committees than a letter from a tenured
or tenure-track professor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What can students do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another facet of the corporatization of the university is the transition of
students into customers. Like any other corporation, the ability to win
customers is the final arbiter of success for modern universities. To that end,
students must vote with their wallets. Choosing a school based on their
willingness to employ full-time faculty will not only help to improve the plight
of adjuncts everywhere, but also makes sense for the student hoping obtain the
best possible education for their tuition dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do I know which schools favor employing full time faculty?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny you should ask! As it happens, this data is included as part of the US
News and World report college rankings. However it does not currently figure
very heavily into the way they calculate their rankings. That&apos;s why I&apos;ve taken
the liberty of compiling the data from US News into a list that is easily
sortable by any of the component information that makes up the
rankings. &lt;a href=&quot;/adjunct/colleges.html&quot;&gt;Feel free to give it a try.&lt;/a&gt; Universities
often claim that these rankings are not meaningful (at least, the ones who don&apos;t
get ranked as highly as they would like do), but the fact is, they matter. They
are often the first place a student will look to begin evaluating colleges. As
the self-appointed arbiters of education quality, US News has an opportunity and
a responsibility to use their influence to push universities towards a higher
standard. Adjuncts have pushed for years to improve their situation, but it is
unlikely universities are going to listen to them. Only when the exploitation of
adjuncts starts to have a negative effect on their enrollment numbers and
tuition revenue are universities going to start making changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to exposing the data surrounding percentage of full-time faculty at
each university, I&apos;ve also created a new metric called &quot;Professors per Dollar&quot;
which is the ratio of full-time faculty at a school to the tuition cost. This is
an attempt to determine which schools are providing the best value in terms of
quality education. College tuition is one of the most expensive purchases you
will make in your life. As a student, you should be confident that your tuition
money is paying for faculty resources to further your education and not
inflating administrator salaries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professors per dollar is not a perfect metric. It&apos;s skewed by schools with very
low tuition costs. The leading private university in this measure is Brigham
Young University, due simply to the fact that the tuition is heavily subsidised
by the Mormon church. It may also be skewed by smaller schools, with a lower
number of students and thus a lower number of professors overall (adjunct or
not). Since these schools do not typically come with a proportionally smaller
price tag, they do worse on this metric, because you&apos;re paying about the same
amount of money for access to fewer resources  than you would at a larger
school. Arguably this could be an accurate way to judge the value of a
particular school, but some students may find smaller schools to be a better fit
regardless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think any one metric is going to present perfect information for every
student to choose a school that suits them best, but all sorts of information
should be made available so that students can make the most informed decision
possible. Overall, I think a higher percentage of full-time faculty indicates
that a school places higher priority on providing a quality education rather
than inflating administrative salaries or building increasingly fancy buildings.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Internet Outrage Fatigue Syndrome (IOFS)]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 1980s were a scary time to be a kid. At least that is if you watched the
evening news. Every night at 6 and 11 you'd be apprised of a…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/internet-odrome-iofs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/internet-odrome-iofs/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The 1980s were a scary time to be a kid. At least that is if you watched the
evening news. Every night at 6 and 11 you&apos;d be apprised of a new mortal danger,
lurking just around the corner. Sometimes it would even be &lt;em&gt;within your own
home&lt;/em&gt;. You&apos;ll hear all about it, after this commercial break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ratings wars among local TV newscasts had by this time long come to a
head. Stations had found that by far the most effective way to garner viewers
was to appeal to emotional instincts. Namely, fear. What thing lurking in your
home can kill you? You clearly need to know. It&apos;s a matter of life or death! How
could you &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; stay tuned until after the next commercial break?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, time marches on. For most everyone under the age of 40, the evening
news is a distant memory. Nowadays, sophisticated paradigms of modernity that
we are, we get our news from the Internet. Streaming through our browsers and
phones at all hours of the night and day, we have access to points,
counter-points, and sometimes even counter-counter-points. We would never be so
silly as to go searching under our kitchen sinks for the boogeyman. How quaint
our forebears were!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hold on a second, what&apos;s this now? A celebrity has said something racist?
Republicans want to shackle all women to the kitchen stove? Investment bankers
are skinning the poor and wearing their skins as suits? Why, this is outrageous!
I ought to...well, certainly the first thing I ought to do is click on this link
and read the article to learn all about it. And then, I must share it! With an
appropriately witty rejoinder of my own, I could garner likes and retweets in
the dozens, if not hundreds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was close. Racism has been solved. Women retain their freedom for another
day. Social justice has been achieved. It&apos;s a good thing I was here, paying
attention! Who knows what might have happened?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, maybe we aren&apos;t so clever as we thought, after all. At the end of the day,
we&apos;re still being emotionally manipulated in order to sell advertising. Instead
of fear, now it&apos;s anger. You&apos;re a good person. You don&apos;t want others to suffer
injustice. So, naturally, when you hear about it, you want to do something. But
what have you done, really, by reading an article? Is that celebrity going to be
less racist now? Are Republican legislators going to suddenly start supporting
women&apos;s rights? It seems unlikely. So what&apos;s being accomplished here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&apos;ve gotten a little off track here. I want to make it clear that I
acknowledge that the issues here are real problems. Racism, sexism, corporate
malfeasance, etc are all serious issues that need to be addressed. Just like the
example of the evening news, preventing your kid from drinking drain cleaner is
definitely a legitimate concern to have. The problem is that the types of
articles mentioned do absolutely nothing to address these issues. Rather, they
cynically manipulate well-intentioned people to drive advertising revenue. In
fact, if we ever did actually beat racism, sexism, etc. many of these &quot;news&quot;
organizations would probably go out of business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from all that, it&apos;s just physically exhausting to be angry all the
time. At some point, you just have to accept that there is pretty much a
never-ending supply of terrible shit going on in the world at any given time,
and there&apos;s not a lot you can do about it. To that end, I recommend tuning out
those who would demand you focus your attention on this or that injustice, and
instead concentrate on things you can personally influence. Life&apos;s too short to
let strangers&apos; profit motives rule your emotions.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Never Buy Retail]]></title><description><![CDATA[In light of a particularly aggressive savings plan this year, I've been thinking
hard about every purchase I make. In doing so I think I've…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/never-buy-retail/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/never-buy-retail/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In light of a particularly aggressive savings plan this year, I&apos;ve been thinking
hard about every purchase I make. In doing so I think I&apos;ve come up with a good
way to tell how likely a particular purchase is to be a waste. For everything
you buy, look at the amount of value you have to add &lt;em&gt;yourself&lt;/em&gt; before it
becomes useful. If you don&apos;t add anything of your own, and consume it
immediately, this means it&apos;s been marked up the maximum possible amount, that is
to say, you&apos;re spending the most amount of money to obtain it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s look at food for example. On one end of the scale you can go to a nice
restaurant. From the moment you walk in the door, you&apos;re whisked to a comfy
table and several real, live human beings will run about, fetching anything you
might desire, fully prepared and ready to eat. At the end of the meal, you&apos;ve
contributed nothing but consumption. The staff of course will clean up after
you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To step it down a notch, you can go to a slightly less fancy restaurant. You
might have to go up to a counter and carry the food &lt;em&gt;all by yourself&lt;/em&gt; to the
table. It&apos;s not much, but it&apos;s something. Chances are you&apos;ll receive some minor
compensation for this effort in the form of lower prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can extend this concept all the way down the &lt;em&gt;ahem&lt;/em&gt; food chain. TV dinners,
fresh cooked meals, growing your own vegetables, etc. I&apos;m not necessarily
advocating that everyone start a farm in their back yard, but it&apos;s helpful to
consider how you might trade a little effort for keeping some more of your money
by bringing your own value to things you consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another good example is housing. My own city, Washington, DC, has been going
through a bit of a population boom over the past several years. As a result the
real estate listing are littered with gems like
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zillow.com/homedetails/1346-Otis-Pl-NW-Washington-DC-20010/472828_zpid/&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. First,
notice that the listing price is over &lt;strong&gt;$370,000&lt;/strong&gt; above Zillow&apos;s estimated value,
based on the amounts comparable homes in the area have sold for. Scroll down a
little more and you&apos;ll see the home last sold for nearly &lt;em&gt;half&lt;/em&gt; the asking
price, and that less than 3 months ago. Clicking through the pictures, it&apos;s
plain to see the seller did an outstanding job renovating this place into a
model of modern luxury. Of course, they expect to be compensated accordingly. All
that value will be transferred from the buyer to the seller in the form of cold,
hard cash. What&apos;s left then for the buyer? We all like to think of homes as
investments, but in this case they&apos;ve essentially just bought a product. All
they can do is hope that people as rich as themselves keep flooding into the
city to buy overpriced homes. There&apos;s no opportunity here to add value
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, and beyond, I&apos;m going to look for more opportunities to add my own
value wherever possible. Buy more raw materials, fewer finished products. As a
happy side effect I&apos;ll also get to learn new skills and get an end result that&apos;s
customized to my exact specifications. Seems like a win all around to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Content Singularity]]></title><description><![CDATA[Think back to the time before the Internet, if you're old enough. How did you
get entertainment? Typically, you had to drive to a store pay…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/the-conteningularity/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/the-conteningularity/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Think back to the time before the Internet, if you&apos;re old enough. How did you
get entertainment? Typically, you had to drive to a store pay some not
insubstantial amount of money, then drive back home and watch your movie or read
your book. If you rented the movie, you&apos;d have to drive back again to return
it. If you wanted to read a newspaper, you had to do the same or arrange a
subscription to have it delivered to your house. Even then, once you finished
reading it (this might take an hour or two, to peruse everything that interested
you), that was it. There wouldn&apos;t be another one until tomorrow. Likewise with
magazines, except you&apos;d have to wait a whole week or even a month for
those. Basically, there was a physical limit to how much entertainment you could
consume at anyone time. TV, was always there of course, but you were limited to
whatever the networks had decided to program at that time. Over time cable
options grew and suddenly there were hundreds of channels providing
entertainment options 24 hours a day. Still, once you flipped through all those
channels, you were left with whatever as on, and there was a good chance that
none of it interested you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet came along and changed all this. Suddenly, there was a world of
information at your fingertips. In the beginning, (I&apos;m referring to the early 90s
here and the advent of widespread consumer Internet. I&apos;m sure many of you are
scoffing heartily about how everything started much much earlier than that) the
Internet too was fairly limited. Information was sparse and of unknown
provenance. The main draw was the ability to connect to real live people all
over the world who wanted to talk about whatever you wanted to talk about at the
moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the present day. As Internet speeds have grown and search
functionality has improved it is now possible to obtain practically any piece of
media that has ever existed at a moment&apos;s notice. Entertainment used to be a
fairly scarce resource. You had to make do with what you could get, when you
could get it, and figure out yourself what to do the rest of the time. Right
now, thanks to Netflix, Amazon Prime, Hulu, and the like most of us lucky enough
to be living in the developed world have access to more entertainment than we
can consume in a lifetime at any moment. We are living in a post-scarcity
entertainment economy, and I don&apos;t think the entertainment industry has caught
on to this yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix, for example, supposedly has at least a petabyte of video stored. If
this were relatively uncompressed HD video at 8 GB/hour (it&apos;s not), that&apos;s
125,000 hours of video. At the 4 hours per day of TV watching the average
American does (so we&apos;re told), this is 85 years worth of content. Granted, not
all of it is necesarily going to be of interest to any one person, but this is a
fairly low estimate, and that&apos;s only the content on one service. Once you add
the books available through your Kindle, the other video services, YouTube,
blogs, news sites, music streaming services, etc, it&apos;s fair to say that the
average person has available to them at any given time, enough entertainment to
last a lifetime. And still, there&apos;s more being created every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&apos;t to say that we should stop. People will continue creating art,
regardless, of how much of it there is, for the same reason they always have:
because there is a truth inside them that they need to communicate to other
people. This is a worthwhile endeavor, and I think it should be encouraged. What
I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; think is going to happen is that the current entertainment industry and
the profits it generates, are unsustainable. Imagine what would happen to the
price of oil if everyone suddenly had an oil well in their living room that
could generate a lifetime worth of oil on demand. That&apos;s about what the
situation is with entertainment. The demand for the kind of
give-your-mind-a-rest, just sit and consume for an hour or two entertainment is
fairly permanently filled. Every new piece of entertainment has to compete not
only with whatever else is on at the time, but with everything that has ever
existed to that point. This is a great time to be an entertainment consumer, but
I think it&apos;s going to be pretty lousy to be an entertainment producer.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Beginnings]]></title><description><![CDATA[It's been a long time coming, but I think it's finally time for me
to shutter GreaterDebater. Suffice it to say, the site never
really…]]></description><link>https://kotsf.com/new-beginnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kotsf.com/new-beginnings/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s been a long time coming, but I think it&apos;s finally time for me
to shutter GreaterDebater. Suffice it to say, the site never
really gained much traction, except maybe among a small, but
dedicated group of spammers. I guess the demand for a site
specifically tailored for arguing on the Internet is not as high
as I had thought. Perhaps people are content to argue on the many
sites where it is only an ancilliary function. Perhaps I didn&apos;t
market as effectively as I could have. Probably some combination
of the above, and other factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any rate, I want to free up the space on the server for new
endeavors, including this blog. The old posts from &lt;em&gt;That&apos;s
Debatable&lt;/em&gt; have been ported to here and will remain accessible in
perpetutity in their own &lt;a href=&quot;/gdarchive&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, I will
plunge forward under the rebranded title you see now. I&apos;m also
writing some new software to make the blog happen. I think the
database/web framework setup is somewhat overkill for my simple
blog. It also favors writing in a web form, which I never
liked. To that end the new blog is statically hosted, with some
simple scripts to convert markdown text to html, pass them through
a template and save to the web server root directly. The whole
thing is pushed to site with mercurial, which makes the workflow
nice for me. It also means I get to do all the writing in emacs,
and who wouldn&apos;t want that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from simplifying my blog life, I have another new project
that has been smoldering on the back burner for a couple years
now. It&apos;s time to finally bring that to the fore, so lookout for
more on that soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone&apos;s new year is off to a great start. See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>